<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-02T14:46:29+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Site Title</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Your Name</name></author><entry><title type="html">From Zero to Software Engineer in Silicon Valley</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Zero to Software Engineer in Silicon Valley" /><published>2016-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley/">&lt;p&gt;In August 2014, I had the opportunity to work at an edtech startup called Zeal Learning as a front-end web developer. Before diving in, let me explain about the “Zero” in the title of this blog post. Considering that I am a Computer Science undergraduate, most people would have expected a certain pedigree at work, even more so in the Valley I suppose. However, this is my very first internship of any kind. Apart from assignments in school, I have never worked on production software. But still, everyone involved in my application process (from school to Zeal) took a gamble and gave me this amazing chance to work in one of the most magical places in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a video call some time prior to arriving in Palo Alto, my CTO touched on the brief history of the startup then moved on to talk about my role of taking charge of the student web product. He mentioned that I will work on the front-end using AngularJS and I remember vividly thinking to myself, “What is that?”. In retrospect, I did not even know much about JS let alone a framework built upon it. I did not even have a GitHub account and have never used Git before. I had no idea what Emacs was. I had never done software testing before too. And I am not even including the many intricate details of software and web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the year, I worked on weekly sprints to improve the product, either fixing bugs or adding features. I had to pick up a lot of things on the job and Google was my best friend just like in school. I was also fortunate to have experienced and patient colleagues around me who are willing to lend me a hand or give advice on how to solve certain problems. Several months later, I was comfortable with the code base and churning features out quicker than before albeit with bugs occasionally. In the later part of the internship, I was also involved in setting up logging using Sentry and Mixpanel as well as UI and Unit testing with Selenium and Jasmine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than gaining technical skills, I also learnt about working in a diverse team. We held daily scrum meetings to update each other about work progress. In addition, I took the opportunity of working with my successful CEO by observing how he ran the company and made decisions day to day to gain some non-technical knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward about 300 days later, I can confidently say that I am a software engineer. I am definitely just scraping the surface of software development and there is still so much more to learn.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">In August 2014, I had the opportunity to work at an edtech startup called Zeal Learning as a front-end web developer. Before diving in, let me explain about the “Zero” in the title of this blog post. Considering that I am a Computer Science undergraduate, most people would have expected a certain pedigree at work, even more so in the Valley I suppose. However, this is my very first internship of any kind. Apart from assignments in school, I have never worked on production software. But still, everyone involved in my application process (from school to Zeal) took a gamble and gave me this amazing chance to work in one of the most magical places in the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22teaser%22=%3E%22zeal-logo.png%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22teaser%22=%3E%22zeal-logo.png%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Startup Weekend Singapore 2015</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startup-weekend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Startup Weekend Singapore 2015" /><published>2015-09-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-09-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startup-weekend</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startup-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;So I have decided to dedicate the very first post of my blog to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.up.co/communities/singapore/singapore/startup-weekend/7299&quot;&gt;Startup Weekend&lt;/a&gt; Singapore 2015 that happened last weekend because of 2 reasons…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fulfill my free ticket promise from NUS Enterprise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I “lost” and I want to keep track of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, a big thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://enterprise.nus.edu.sg/&quot;&gt;NUS Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring the ticket to such an awesome event and getting me fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a special mention to the organisers who did a great job in making the event happen and ensured everything went smoothly together with well-known speakers and judges gracing the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let me bring you through my experience at the event in chronological order. Do note that I entered this event with high expectations of hoping to win it and launch my own startup; I even assembled a team prior to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-one---friday-night&quot;&gt;Day One - Friday Night&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first day which took place from dinner time till about 10pm, those with ideas were asked to pitch in front of all the participants. The top 20 ideas (by polling) will then try to attract people and form teams to work on the ideas during the weekend. To start the ball rolling, I let the only business guy in the team and my roommate during &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.overseas.nus.edu.sg/&quot;&gt;NOC&lt;/a&gt; represent the team and pitch the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our idea actually ended up being the most popular at the end of voting time which indicated that a good number of people wanted to join us. But frankly, we as a team decided against recruiting more team members as we felt there was no need to and we were more comfortable working within the three of us. It may seem like an irrational decision but I felt it was good in the sense that we respected each other’s decision and moved forward as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-two---saturday&quot;&gt;Day Two - Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day of the event, I arrived a little earlier than my teammates to look for a space for us to work during the weekend. That was the result of the place you see in the picture below (I can’t imagine more people with us in that small space).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;_config.yml&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with about 30 hours to the final presentation on Sunday evening, the three of us worked relentlessly mainly on market research, product validation and developing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we were also fortunate to have many smart and experienced mentors coming in to guide us. It was some sort of a double-edged sword to have the mentors advising us. One was that there were many great advice, but there were also too many of it. This taught us to understand and evaluate if a particular one is suitable for us to heed. Nonetheless, coming from a technical background, I really appreciate every single advice because they taught me something about building a product and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-three---sunday&quot;&gt;Day Three - Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D-Day is here. Like many real startups, we pivoted a couple of times and landed on something that we felt good to work on. My fellow developer and I were busy building the prototype while my ex-roommate was working on his pitch deck. It felt like we figured things out and were working towards realising our vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However as can be gathered at the start of this blog post, the team did not win, not even third. But I can say that I am extremely proud of the work that we produced considering the short amount of time we had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realised that instead of feeling down and disappointed, this is actually a stepping stone in the journey to being an entrepreneur. In fact, isn’t one of the traits in an entrepreneur being resilient? This “lost” will definitely remind me to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">So I have decided to dedicate the very first post of my blog to Startup Weekend Singapore 2015 that happened last weekend because of 2 reasons…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22teaser%22=%3E%22sw-logo.jpg%22,%20%22feature%22=%3E%22sw.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22teaser%22=%3E%22sw-logo.jpg%22,%20%22feature%22=%3E%22sw.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>